Finding Aid for Collegiate Institute for Values and Science (University of Michigan) records
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Alan Price Records
  - Classified Research Policy Review
    The Classified Research Policy Review subseries consists of .4 linear feet of materials dating from 1976 and 1985-1987. The clippings subseries contains local news clippings which relate to the classified research policy review that took place over the course of several years at the University of Michigan. The correspondence, memos and reports include materials and correspondence from various student groups, researchers and administrators on campus voicing their views on the events related to the policy review.
    - Clippings
      - 1985 (Box 7)
      - 1986 (Box 7)
      - 1987 (Box 7)
    - Correspondence, memos and reports
      - 1976 (Box 7)
      - 1985 (Box 7)
      - 1986, 5 folders (Box 7)
      - 1987 (Box 7)
  - Nuclear Free Zone
    The Nuclear Free Zone subseries consists of .5 linear feet of materials dating from 1983 through 1985. The clippings subseries consists of ads for the Nuclear Free Zone movement, as well as news clippings (both national and local) which discuss this movement to turn Ann Arbor into a zone which would not support or contribute to the production of nuclear weapons in any way. The correspondence, memos and reports subseries relate to the movement as well, and tend to relate to various University administrators' reactions to student and community action.
    - Clippings
      - August-September 1984 (Box 7)
      - October 1984 (Box 7)
      - November 1984 (Box 7)
      - December 1984 (Box 7)
      - January-July 1985 (Box 7)
      - August-December 1985 (Box 7)
    - Correspondence, memos and reports
      - December 1983 (Box 7)
      - August 1984 (Box 7)
      - September 1984, 3 folders (Box 7)
      - October 1984, 3 folders (Box 7)
      - November-December 1984 (Box 7)
      - 1985 (Box 7)
  - Peace Studies
    The Peace Studies subseries consists of .1 linear feet of material dating from 1985 through 1986. The materials relate to specific lectures, courses, and activities on campus and in the Ann Arbor community related to peace theory and activism.
    - Clippings
      - 1985-1986 (Box 8)
    - Correspondence, memos and reports
      - 1985 undated (Box 8)
      - Nuclear Arms Control Simulation (1985) (Box 8)
  - Research News and Information
    The Research News and Information subseries consists of .5 linear feet of materials dating from 1981-1987 and 1991. The Clippings subseries brings together a broad range of news materials, both national and local, which relate generally to the controversy over DOD-funded classified research projects at the University and the ensuing protests. The correspondence, memos and reports subseries contains statistical reports on DOD grants to the University, reactions by administrators to press coverage, reactions to meetings and student protests on campus, and text of and reactions to speeches.
    - Clippings
      - 1981 (Box 8)
      - January-April 1982 (Box 8)
      - May-August 1982 (Box 8)
      - September-December 1982 (Box 8)
      - January-March 1983 (Box 8)
      - April-July 1983 (Box 8)
      - August-October 1983 (Box 8)
      - November-December 1983 (Box 8)
      - 1984, 2 folders (Box 8)
      - 1985, 2 folders (Box 8)
      - 1986-7 (Box 8)
    - Correspondence, memos and reports
      - 1983 (Box 8)
      - January-June 1984 (Box 8)
      - July-December 1984 (Box 8)
      - 1985 (Box 8)
      - 1986 (Box 8)
      - 1991 (Box 8)
  - Research Policy Committee
    The Research Policy Committee subseries consists of .4 linear feet of materials dating from 1981 through 1985. These are official committee materials including agendas, reports discussed at meetings, correspondence between members, and minutes of meetings. These materials provide especially valuable insight into the considerations involved in policy formation and construction of other public statements in regard to sensitive research.
    - Committee Materials
      - 1981 (Box 8)
      - February-May 1982 (Box 8)
      - October 1982 (Box 8)
      - November 1982 (Box 8)
      - December 1982 (Box 8)
      - January 1983 (Box 8)
      - February 1983 (Box 8)
      - March 1983 (Box 8)
      - April 1983 (Box 8)
      - May 1983 (Box 8)
      - June 1983 (Box 8)
      - July-August 1983 (Box 8)
      - October-December 1983 (Box 8)
      - 1984 (Box 8)
      - 1985 (Box 8)
  - Strategic Defense Initiative ("Star Wars")
    The Strategic Defense Initiative ("Star Wars") subseries consists of .2 linear feet of material dating from 1985 through 1986. The materials relate to the University of Michigan's involvement in and reaction to the planned DOD initiative.
    - Clippings
      - 1985 (Box 9)
      - 1986 (Box 9)
    - Correspondence, memos and reports
      - January-August 1985 (Box 9)
      - September-December 1985 (Box 9)
      - 1986 (Box 9)
  - University Research Initiative (URI)
    The University Research Initiative (URI) subseries consists of .2 linear feet of material dating from 1985 through 1986. The University Research Initiative refers to the Department of Defense's program to encourage defense-related research at U.S. Universities. The materials in this series relate to the University of Michigan's involvement in the program, and its relationship with the DOD and with other Universities in the program.
    - Clippings 1986 (Box 9)
    - Correspondence, memos and reports
      - 1985 (Box 9)
      - January-June 1986 (Box 9)
      - July-December 1986 (Box 9)
  - University Research Instrumentation Program
    The University Research Instrumentation Program subseries consists of materials from 1982 and 1983 concerning the University's grant proposals to the Department of Defense to obtain major research equipment. The materials consist primarily of correspondence, forms, and financial documentation.
    - 1982-1983 (Box 9)